Guide to the Thornton Wilder Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1915-1991; Series II; 21.27; (56 boxes)
  - PLAYS: ORIGINAL WORKS BY THORNTON WILDER
    - "Mr. Bozzy"
      - Typescript, n.d. (Box 77, Folder 2038)
    - "Mrs. Gump"
      - Manuscript notebook, [1917] (Box 77, Folder 2039)
    - "Noah's Ark"
      - Typescript, annotated, n.d. (Box 77, Folder 2040)
      - Typescript of ideas for Acts II and III (Box 77, Folder 2041)
    - "Old Houses, Old Houses"
      - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 77, Folder 2042)
    - Our Town
      - Holograph manuscript: "First full script--Act II missing", n.d. (Box 78, Folder 2043)
      - Holograph manuscript fragment of Act II, n.d. (Box 78, Folder 2044)
      - Holograph manuscript: "Stage manager's part", n.d. (Box 78, Folder 2045)
      - Holograph manuscript: "Second script" (incomplete) (Box 78, Folder 2046)
      - Holograph manuscript and typescript, corrected and annotated (Box 78, Folder 2047-2049)
      - Galley proof, corrected and annotated, 1937 May 14
      - Typescript of Preface, 1938 (Box 78, Folder 2050)
      - Holograph manuscripts of production directions, 1938, n.d. (Box 78, Folder 2051)
      - Typescript carbons of costume directions, [1938?] (Box 78, Folder 2052)
      - Flyer for first production annotated by Wilder, 1938 (Box 78, Folder 2053)
      - Royalty statements, [1938?] (Box 78, Folder 2054)
      - Scripts for London production of 1946 (Box 78, Folder 2055-2057)
      - Corrections to the text of the London production, 1946 (Box 78, Folder 2058)
      - Advertisements, 1938-75, n.d. (Box 78, Folder 2059)
      - Posters
      - Programs, 1938-48, n.d. (Box 78, Folder 2060-2061)
      - Programs, 1948-75, n.d. (Box 79, Folder 2062-2067)
      - Magazine articles, 1940-76, n.d. (Box 79, Folder 2068-2070)
        See also: Oversize, Box 163, folder 3910 and Oversize, Box 163, folder 3917
      - Newspaper clippings, 1938-39 (Box 79, Folder 2071-2072)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1938-39 (Box 80, Folder 2073-2077)
      - Newspaper clippings on Wilder's appearances as Stage Manager, 1938-46, n.d. (Box 80, Folder 2078)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1940-74, n.d. (Box 80, Folder 2079-2087)
      - Tributes and comments collected by Bill Roerich for the 25th anniversary of Our Town, 1963 (Box 80, Folder 2087a)
        Includes tributes by Martha Scott, Alida Stanley and Teresa Wright
        Accompanied by ALS from TW to IW, 1963 Feb 6
    - Our Town: Adaptations
      Film by Sol Lesser
      - Memo concerning film rights, n.d.
      - "Plan for Screen Treatment": typescript carbons, 1939 Sep (Box 80, Folder 2089)
      - "First Rough Draft Screenplay": typescript carbon, 1939 Sep-Oct (Box 81, Folder 2090)
      - "Revised First Draft", 1939 Oct 20 (Box 81, Folder 2091)
      - "Second Draft Screenplay", 1939 Nov (Box 81, Folder 2092)
        With: memo by Wilder concerning final dialogue, 1939 Dec 15
      - "Second Draft Script", 1939 Dec 15 (Box 81, Folder 2093)
      - "Final Shooting Script", 1940 Jan 9 (Box 81, Folder 2094)
      - Publicity material, 1940 May (Box 81, Folder 2095)
      - Reviews, 1940 (Box 81, Folder 2096)
      - "Concert Sequence from the Film Our Town, Composed for Sol Lesser's film production of Thornton Wilder's classic American play, Our Town. Aaron Copland, (1940)
        Score reproduced from manuscript copy.
        Inscribed: "To Thornton from Stanislaw"
      - " Our Town: Three Piano Excerpts from the Film Score by Aaron Copland," printed score, [1945] (Box 81, Folder 2096a)
      - Film by Schrank
        - Script: typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 81, Folder 2097)
      - Radio Script for "Fourth Act"
        - Script: typescript carbon, [1944] (Box 81, Folder 2097a)
          Text of interview with Wilder for "Contact" and of a brief "fourth act" set in wartime
      - "Arthur Hopkins Presents"
        - Script for radio adaptation by Wyllis Cooper, 1944 Apr 19 (Box 81, Folder 2098)
        - Newspaper clippings, 1944 (Box 81, Folder 2099)
      - "Theatre Guild on the Air"
        - Script for radio adaptation by Erik Barnouw, 1946 Sep 29 (Box 81, Folder 2100)
        - Programs for broadcast, 1946 Sep (Box 81, Folder 2101)
      - "Art Carney Show"
        - "Final revise" of script for televison show, 1959 Nov 9 (Box 81, Folder 2102)
      - NBC production
        - Newspaper clippings, 1977 (Box 81, Folder 2103)
    - Our Town: Translations
      - French
        - Mauclair, Jean: "Nôtre petite ville": typescript carbon, 1946 (Box 82, Folder 2104)
          Includes letter on translation by Thornton Wilder, 1946 Apr, and press release, 1944
        - Thériault, Yvon: "Nôtre petite ville": typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 82, Folder 2105)
      - Hungarian
        - "A Mi Kis Varosunk": typescript photocopy, n.d. (Box 82, Folder 2106)
      - Italian
        - Petrucci, L. M.: "La Nostra Citta": typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 82, Folder 2107)
    - Our Town: related material
      - Book promotional material, 1938, n.d. (Box 82, Folder 2108)
      - Caricature sketches, n.d. (Box 82, Folder 2109)
      - Children's art exhibit, 1959 (Box 82, Folder 2110)
      - Facsimile reproduction of a page, n.d. (Box 82, Folder 2111)
      - Instructional material, 1946-72 (Box 82, Folder 2112)
      - Music score and recording for TV version starring Frank Sinatra (Box 82, Folder 2113)
      - Music score: "Our Town", 1969, n.d. (Box 82, Folder 2114)
      - Parody tribute to Abraham Ribicoff, "Abe's Town", 1962 (Box 82, Folder 2115)
      - Press releases: photocopies, n.d. (Box 82, Folder 2116)
      - Ticket stubs and miscellaneous sales records, 1938-46, n.d. (Box 82, Folder 2117-2118)
    - "The Pilgrims"
      - Holograph manuscript, 1931 (Box 82, Folder 2119)
    - Play compilations
      - Playbills, 1917-81, n.d. (Box 82, Folder 2120-2121)
    - Plays for Bleeker Street
      Includes "Infancy" and "Youth" from The Seven Ages of Man and "Lust" from The Seven Deadly Sins
      - Holograph production notes, [1961?] (Box 82, Folder 2122)
      - Playbills, 1961-63 (Box 82, Folder 2123)
      - Advertisements, 1961 (Box 82, Folder 2124)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1962, n.d. (Box 82, Folder 2125)
    - "The Primrose Path"
      - Typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 82, Folder 2126)
    - "Pullman Car Hiawatha"
      - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 83, Folder 2127)
      - Holograph manuscript, corrected, n.d. (Box 83, Folder 2128)
      - Playbills, n.d. (Box 83, Folder 2129)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1962-63, n.d. (Box 83, Folder 2130)
    - "Queens of France"
      - Holograph manuscript, 1930 (Box 83, Folder 2131)
      - Holograph manuscript, 1930 (Box 83, Folder 2132)
      - Typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 83, Folder 2133)
      - Typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 83, Folder 2134)
      - Playbill, 1932 Mar 15 (Box 83, Folder 2135)
      - Newspaper clipping, 1962 Mar (Box 83, Folder 2136)
      - Translation into French by Ida de Becker, n.d. (Box 83, Folder 2137)
    - "The Reformers"
      - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 83, Folder 2138)
      - Manuscript notebook, n.d. (Box 83, Folder 2139)
      - Manuscript notebook, n.d. (Box 83, Folder 2140)
      - Manuscript notebook, n.d. (Box 83, Folder 2141)
    - "Rivers Under the Earth"
      - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 83, Folder 2142)
    - "The Rocket"
      - Typescript corrected, n.d. (Box 83, Folder 2143)
    - "The Russian Princess"
      - Playbill annotated by Wilder, n.d. (Box 83, Folder 2144)
    - The Seven Ages of Man
      - "Infancy"
        - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 83, Folder 2145)
        - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 83, Folder 2146)
        - Manuscript notebook, n.d. (Box 83, Folder 2147)
          Includes notes for "Childhood"
        - Typescript, n.d. (Box 83, Folder 2148)
        - Typescript, n.d. (Box 83, Folder 2149)
      - "Childhood"
        - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 83, Folder 2150)
        - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 83, Folder 2151)
        - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 83, Folder 2152)
        - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 83, Folder 2153)
        - Printed version in Atlantic Monthly, 1960 Nov (Box 83, Folder 2154)
      - "Youth"
        - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 83, Folder 2155)
        - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 83, Folder 2156)
        - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 83, Folder 2157)
        - Typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 84, Folder 2158)
        - Typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 84, Folder 2159)
        - Newspaper clippings, 1961-72, n.d. (Box 84, Folder 2160)
        - Posters for German version of "Infancy" and "Childhood"
      - "Old Age"
        - Holograph manuscript fragment, n.d. (Box 84, Folder 2161)
    - The Seven Deadly Sins
      - Avarice: "Cement Hands"
        - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 84, Folder 2162)
        - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 84, Folder 2163)
      - Envy: "A Ringing of Doorbells"
        - Holograph manuscript, [1933] (Box 84, Folder 2164)
      - Lust: "Someone from Assisi"
        - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 84, Folder 2165)
        - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 84, Folder 2166)
        - Typescript mimeographs, n.d. (Box 84, Folder 2167-2168)
        - German translation: "Jemand aus Assisi," typescript (Box 84, Folder 2169-2170)
      - Pride: "Bernice"
        - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 84, Folder 2171)
        - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 84, Folder 2172)
        - Typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 84, Folder 2173)
        - Typescript carbons, n.d. (Box 84, Folder 2174-2175)
        - Typescript and page proof, German translation: "Berenike" (Box 84, Folder 2176-2177)
      - Sloth: "The Wreck on the 5:25"
        - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 84, Folder 2178)
        - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 84, Folder 2179)
        - Typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 84, Folder 2180)
        - Typescript carbons, n.d. (Box 84, Folder 2181-2182)
        - German translation: "Die Trägheit," typescript (Box 84, Folder 2183)
      - Wrath
        - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 84, Folder 2184)
        - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 84, Folder 2185)
      - Newspaper clippings on German performances, 1957, n.d. (Box 84, Folder 2186)
    - "Shadow of a Doubt"
      - Typescript, 1942 (Box 85, Folder 2187)
    - Skin of Our Teeth
      - Holograph manuscript notes, 1942, n.d. (Box 85, Folder 2188-2190)
      - Holograph manuscript (page 1 missing), n.d. (Box 85, Folder 2191)
      - Holograph manuscript, Acts II and III (Box 85, Folder 2192)
      - Holograph manuscript fragment, Act III, n.d. (Box 85, Folder 2193)
      - Typescript, corrected, Act I, n.d. (Box 85, Folder 2194)
      - Typescript, corrected, Act II, n.d. (Box 85, Folder 2195)
      - Typescript carbon, complete: "First Version", 1942 (Box 85, Folder 2196)
      - Typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 85, Folder 2197-2198)
      - Typescript mimeograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 86, Folder 2199)
      - Galley proof, n.d.
      - Copies of script for the Myerberg production, n.d. (Box 86, Folder 2200-2201)
      - Playbills, 1942-77, n.d. (Box 87, Folder 2202-2210)
      - Posters
      - Advertisements, 1942, n.d. (Box 88, Folder 2211)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1942-47 (Box 88, Folder 2212-2223)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1948-91, n.d. (Box 88, Folder 2224-2231)
    - The Skin of Our Teeth: Adaptations
      - "Television version": typescript carbon and clippings, 1968, n.d. (Box 88, Folder 2232-2233)
      - Adaptation as musical by Mary Ellen Bute
        - Typescript, corrected, 1968 Aug (Box 89, Folder 2234)
        - Typescript carbons, n.d. (Box 89, Folder 2235-2236)
        - Holograph manuscript note on the Bute version, n.d. (Box 89, Folder 2237)
        - Typescript carbon of comments by Isabel Wilder, 1969 May 9
    - The Skin of Our Teeth: Translations
      - French translation by Ida de Becker, typescript carbons, n.d. (Box 89, Folder 2238-2239)
    - The Skin of Our Teeth: Related Material
      - American Bicentennial Theater production: correspondence, notes, press releases and clippings, 1975-76 (Box 89, Folder 2240-2241)
      - Caricatures, 1942, n.d. (Box 89, Folder 2242)
      - Program notes draft, typescript, 1966 (Box 89, Folder 2243)
      - Program, autographed by cast members of a Texas production, n.d. (Box 89, Folder 2244)
      - Pulitzer Prize: newspaper clippings, 1943, n.d. (Box 89, Folder 2245)
      - Saturday Review of Literature controversy
        - December 1942-January 1943 issues containing "The Skin of Whose Teeth?" articles by Joseph Campbell and Henry Morton Robinson and responses to their charge of plagiarism, 1942-43 (Box 89, Folder 2246)
        - December 1942 issue of Theatre Arts Monthly covering the discussion, 1942 Dec (Box 89, Folder 2247)
        - Miscellaneous articles, 1943, n.d. (Box 89, Folder 2248)
    - "The Soldier and the Geisha"
      - Typescript carbon, 1952 (Box 89, Folder 2249)
    - "Such Things Only Happen in Books"
      - Holograph manuscripts, 1931 (Box 89, Folder 2250)
    - "Three Minute Playlets for Three Persons:" collected ms.
      - Manuscript volume, 1920-21
        Holographs, corrrected, of twelve plays: "1. Nascuntur Poetae; 2. Proserpina and the Devil; 3. The Other Fanny Olcott; 4. The Last Miracle of the Graal; 5. The Penny that Beauty Spent; 6. Solus Inter Deos Potens 7. Brother Fire; 8. The Angel on the Ship; 9. The Message and Jehane; 10. Childe Roland to the Dark Tower Came; 11. The Death of the Centaur; 12. Not for Leviathan"
        Holograph annotation: "Book bought, Oct 30, 1920, Rome."
    - "Three Minute Playlets for Three Persons:" single titles
      - The first ten plays are in the order Wilder placed them in; the remainder, which he did not number, but did identify as parts of this group, are in alphabetical order.
        - Original holograph title page draft, n.d. (Box 89, Folder 2251)
      - "The Song of Maria Bentedos: No. 2"
        - Typescript and mimeograph (Box 89, Folder 2252)
      - "St. Francis Lake: No. 4"
        - Holograph manuscript and typescript (Box 89, Folder 2253)
      - "Brother Fire: No. 5"
        - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 89, Folder 2254)
        - Printed copy, 1916 May (Box 89, Folder 2255)
      - "Two Christmas Interludes: No. 5 B"
        - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 89, Folder 2256)
      - "Solus inter Deos Potens: No. 6"
        - Manuscript notebook, n.d. (Box 89, Folder 2257)
          Also contains "The Message and Jehane"; "The Marriage We Deplore"; "Measure for Measure: A Sonnet"; "The Ballade of Heros in Hell": "That Other Fanny Olcott"; "An Imaginary Preface"; "The Last Miracle of the Grail": "Preface to Plutarch's 'Anthony'; and notes
        - Typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 89, Folder 2258)
      - "The Message and Jehanne: No. 7"
        - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 89, Folder 2259)
        - Typescripts, n.d. (Box 89, Folder 2260)
        - Playbill, 1917 Dec 20 (Box 89, Folder 2261)
        - Printed copy, 1945 Feb (Box 89, Folder 2262)
      - "The Death of the Centaur: No. 11"
        - Holograph manuscript (title "Centaurs"), n.d. (Box 90, Folder 2263)
        - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 90, Folder 2264)
        - Typescripts and printed copy (Box 90, Folder 2265)
      - "The Walled City: No. 12"
        - Manuscript notebook, n.d. (Box 90, Folder 2266)
        - Printed copy, 1918 Mar (Box 90, Folder 2267)
      - "The Penny that Beauty Spent: No. 12"
        - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 90, Folder 2268)
        - Printed copy, 1918 Jun (Box 90, Folder 2269)
      - "Childe Roland to the Dark Tower Came: No. 13"
        - Holograph manuscripts and fragment (Box 90, Folder 2270)
          Includes holograph draft of "The Two Helenas" ("Childe Roland")
        - Typescript carbon and program, 1962, n.d. (Box 90, Folder 2271)
      - "Anastacia's Tower"
        - Typescript, n.d. (Box 90, Folder 2272)
      - "And the Sea Shall Give Up Its Dead"
        - Printed copy in S4N, 1923 Jan-Feb (Box 90, Folder 2273)
      - "The Angel on the Ship"
        - Printed copies in Yale Literary Magazine, 1917 Oct (Box 90, Folder 2274)
      - "The Angel that Troubled the Waters"
        - German translation with "Nascuntur Poetae"in Corona, 1940 (Box 90, Folder 2275)
      - "Flamingo Red"
        - Printed copy, 1916 Jan (Box 90, Folder 2276)
      - "The Flight into Egypt"
        - Danish translation, proofs, n.d. (Box 90, Folder 2277)
        - German translation for Radio Zurich, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 90, Folder 2278)
      - "Hast Thou Considered My Servant Job?"
        - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 90, Folder 2279)
        - German translation, typescript carbon, 1930 (Box 90, Folder 2280)
      - "In Praise of Guyenemer"
        - Holograph manuscript headed "Gynemer", n.d. (Box 90, Folder 2281)
        - Typescript carbon, 1918 (Box 90, Folder 2282)
        - Printed copy in Yale Literary Magazine, 1918 Dec (Box 90, Folder 2283)
      - "Proserpina and the Devil"
        - Printed copy, 1916 Dec (Box 90, Folder 2284)
      - "That Other Fanny Olcott"
        - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 90, Folder 2285)
        - Typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 90, Folder 2286)
        - Printed copy in Yale Literary Magazine, 1918 Jun (Box 90, Folder 2287)
      - Miscellaneous notes, n.d. (Box 90, Folder 2288)
      - Playbill, 1919 Dec (Box 90, Folder 2289)
    - The Trumpet Shall Sound
      - Manuscript notebooks, n.d. (Box 90, Folder 2290-2293)
      - Manuscript fragments, n.d. (Box 91, Folder 2294)
      - Holograph manuscript: Act IV, n.d. (Box 91, Folder 2295)
      - Typescript carbon, complete, n.d. (Box 91, Folder 2296)
      - Typescript carbon, Act I, n.d. (Box 91, Folder 2297)
      - Typescript carbon, annotated, incomplete, n.d. (Box 91, Folder 2298-2299)
      - Printed copy in Yale Literary Magazine, 1919 Oct (Box 91, Folder 2300)
      - Playbills, 1926-27 (Box 91, Folder 2301)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1927 (Box 91, Folder 2302)
    - "The Unerring Instinct"
      - Holograph manuscripts, n.d. (Box 91, Folder 2303-2304)
      - Typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 91, Folder 2305)
    - "Vecy-Segal"
      - Manuscript notebooks, n.d. (Box 91, Folder 2306-2308)
      - Typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 91, Folder 2309)
    - "Villa Rhabani"
      - Manuscript notebook: Acts I and II (Box 91, Folder 2310)
      - Manuscript notebook: Act III, n.d. (Box 91, Folder 2311)
      - Typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 92, Folder 2312)
    - "The Wine of Violence"
      - Typescript fragment, n.d. (Box 92, Folder 2313)
  - PLAYS: ADAPTATIONS BY WILDER
    - "The Beaux Strategem" by George Farquhar
      - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 92, Folder 2314)
      - Typescript, n.d. (Box 92, Folder 2315)
    - "A Doll's House" by Henrik Ibsen
      - Playbill, 1937 (Box 92, Folder 2316)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1937 (Box 92, Folder 2317)
    - "The Rape of Lucrece" by Andre Obey
      - Playbills, 1932-64, n.d. (Box 92, Folder 2318)
      - Poster, [1932]
        Signed by Robert Russel
      - Newspaper clippings, 1932 (Box 92, Folder 2319)
    - "The Sea-Gull" by Anton Chekhov
      - Typescript carbon, corrected by Wilder and others, of Phoenix Theatre rehearsal copy, 1954 (Box 92, Folder 2320)
        With: ALS from Isabel Wilder to Donald Gallup, 1954 Jul 14
    - Untitled and unidentified plays
      - Holograph manuscript fragments, n.d. (Box 92, Folder 2321-2324)
      - Manuscript notebook of incomplete plays, n.d. (Box 92, Folder 2325)
  - NOVELS
    - The Bridge of San Luis Rey
      - "Early manuscript," fragments, n.d. (Box 93, Folder 2326-2327)
      - Manuscript notebook ("Cahier I"), 1926-27 (Box 93, Folder 2328)
      - Manuscript notebook ("Cahier II"), 1926-27 (Box 93, Folder 2329)
      - Typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 93, Folder 2330)
      - Typescript, corrected, incomplete, n.d. (Box 93, Folder 2331)
      - Bound dummy, 1927 (Box 93, Folder 2332)
      - Galley proof, marked, incomplete, n.d.
      - Galley proof, marked of Book IV, n.d.
      - Page proof of title page, 1927 (Box 93, Folder 2333)
      - Advance copies of proof pages for copyright purposes, with note by Lewis S. Baer, 1927 (Box 93, Folder 2334-2336)
      - Bound proof for copyright, 1927 (Box 94, Folder 2337)
      - Page proof of English edition, 1927 Sep (Box 94, Folder 2338)
      - Book jackets for both editions, 1927 (Box 94, Folder 2339)
      - Printing history, 1927-49, 1949 (Box 94, Folder 2340)
      - Best-seller lists, 1927-28 (Box 94, Folder 2341)
      - Illustrations and cartoons, 1973, n.d. (Box 94, Folder 2342)
        Includes pen and ink drawing of the bridge by Paul Alexander Bartlett, 1973 May
      - Newspaper clippings, 1927-29 (Box 94, Folder 2343-2348)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1927-29 (Box 94, Folder 2349-2354)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1931-70, n.d. (Box 94, Folder 2355-2357)
      - Pulitzer Prize: announcements, 1928 (Box 94, Folder 2358)
    - The Bridge of San Luis Rey: Adaptations
      - Film version, 1929: newspaper clippings, 1929, 1944 (Box 95, Folder 2359-2362)
      - Du Pont network television version: newspaper clippings, 1957 (Box 95, Folder 2363)
    - The Bridge of San Luis Rey: Translations
      - German translation by Herlitschka: corrected proof pages, 1933 (Box 95, Folder 2364)
      - German adaptation by Ludi Claire: typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 95, Folder 2365)
      - Proposal for Italian television version typescript carbon, 1958 (Box 95, Folder 2366)
      - Italian translation by Lauro de Bosis: newspaper clippings, 1963
    - The Bridge of San Luis Rey: Related Material
      - Illustrations for Time Readers edition, 1963: galley proofs, n.d.
      - Comments by Wilder on interpretations of The Bridge, typescript photocopies, n.d. (Box 95, Folder 2367)
      - Cliff Notes, 1966
    - "The Brotherhood of the Ascesis"
      - Manuscript notebook, incomplete, n.d. (Box 95, Folder 2368)
      - Typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 95, Folder 2369)
      - Holograph note, 1923 (Box 95, Folder 2370)
    - The Cabala
      - Manuscript fragments, n.d. (Box 95, Folder 2371)
      - Holograph manuscript and typescript, corrected, titled "Notes of a Roman Student" (Box 95, Folder 2372)
      - Editorial memo by H. G. Fuller, n.d. (Box 95, Folder 2373)
      - Dummy, 1926 (Box 95, Folder 2374)
      - Galley proof sheet, corrected by Wilder, n.d.
      - Book jackets, 1926 (Box 95, Folder 2375)
      - Photocopy of presentation inscription, n.d. (Box 95, Folder 2376)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1926-29 (Box 96, Folder 2377-2380)
        See also: Oversize, Box 169, folder 3969
      - Newspaper clippings on Cabala reissue, 1968 (Box 96, Folder 2381)
      - German translation by Herlitschka: corrected and annotated copy (Box 96, Folder 2382)
      - Articles on German version, 1929, 1931 (Box 96, Folder 2383)
    - "Chinese Story"
      - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 96, Folder 2384)
    - The Eighth Day
      - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 96, Folder 2385-2390)
      - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 97, Folder 2391)
      - Holograph manuscript and typescript, corrected: Prologue and Book I (Box 97, Folder 2392)
      - Holograph manuscript and typescript, corrected: Book II (Box 97, Folder 2393)
      - Holograph manuscript and typescript, corrected: Books III and IV (Box 97, Folder 2394)
      - Holograph manuscript and typescript, corrected: Books V and VI (Box 97, Folder 2395)
      - Early typescript of "The Elms" section, n.d. (Box 97, Folder 2396)
      - Photocopies of draft sent by Wilder to Isabel Wilder, 1966 (Box 98, Folder 2397-2404)
      - Photocopies of draft sent by Wilder to Isabel Wilder, 1966 (Box 98, Folder 2405-2411)
      - Setting typescript, corrected: "First Master Copy", 1967 (Box 99, Folder 2412-2416)